<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baldurs Gate 2 on Jefklak&#39;s Codex</title>
    <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/baldurs-gate-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Baldurs Gate 2 on Jefklak&#39;s Codex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/baldurs-gate-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BG2 Solo Blade: A Report</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-solo-blade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-solo-blade/</guid>
      <description>Report Content  Soloing - the Introduction The Blade Kit explained Used Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate II Setup Part 1: Irenicus&amp;rsquo; Dungeon Part 2: The Circus Tent &amp;amp; Slums Slaves Part 3: A Tanner &amp;amp; More Slaves Part 4: The Astral Prison Part 5: Daystar &amp;amp; Mae&amp;rsquo;Var Part 6: Some Beholders &amp;amp; a Lich Part 7: Druid Grove &amp;amp; Guarded Compound Part 8: Planar Sphere &amp;amp; Kangaxx! Part 9: The Shadow Temple</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Mage Talk</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-magetalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-magetalk/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered whatever the heck those crazy Arcane spellcasters say every time they unleash one of their spells upon you? It&#39;s actually very simple and stands for the chosen spell&#39;s spell school (abjuration, evocation, ...). Male and female voices are of course different, and the pronunciations vary too sometimes (Vita Mortis [Carero]/[Calia]?). All formulaes are actually Latin, and Latin is often pronounced differently depending on the dialect. Here is a quick overview:  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Parties</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-parties/</guid>
      <description>Party Number TWO - 06 Jan. 2006 (download link no longer available) Party Numer TWO - 06 Jan. 2006   Attitude: Xandarr, my main character. I decided to create a melee divine spellcaster, for the very first time, since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Arcane Magic way too much. I ended up with three members who are able to cast divinity spells, which is awesome. Xandarr is also the main melee mob killer, besides Keldorn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Spell Protection</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-spellprotection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-spellprotection/</guid>
      <description>Lots of misunderstanding exist for breaking through the spell protections of high level spell casting creatures. This guide is an almost exact copy of zvijers guide at the gone forgotten wars forum, also carried on by &amp;ldquo;The Hero&amp;rsquo;s Guide to a Successful adventure&amp;rdquo;. I found this to be very informative and vital for solo runs. The strategies explain mage protections in weimer&amp;rsquo;s Tactics modification.
All credits go to Xyx, Alson and Littiz for their Spell Reference Guide!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPG Concepts: Items</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-items/</guid>
      <description>Items present in the World Did you ever play an RPG, wondering why the world is so empty? Do you ever wonder, while entering a noble house without any real permission, why all closets are empty or not even openable? If you happen to like looting everybody&amp;rsquo;s treasure chests, bepare to be disappointed as some wealthy NPCs keep two single gold pieces in them. Wow! The RPG world &amp;ldquo;contents&amp;rdquo; should also reflect the current neighbourhood you&amp;rsquo;re travelling in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BG2/Infinity Engine Mods</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-mods/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s modular Roleplaying game Neverwinter Nights 2 was released. NWN is well-known for its overwhelming amounth of fan-made modules and even whole Community Packs. This is the result of BioWare&amp;rsquo;s powerful Aurora Engine toolkit, which came packaged with the game. So actually it&amp;rsquo;s not that strange the game gets so much attention - take a look at UT2004&amp;rsquo;s numberous modifications or Total Conversions: with UnrealEd this is all possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>