<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Castlevania on Jefklaks Codex</title>
    <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/castlevania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Castlevania on Jefklaks Codex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/castlevania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Aria of Sorrow: a retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/aria-of-sorrow-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/aria-of-sorrow-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Calling Aria of Sorrow the best handheld Castlevania is no small feat: they&amp;rsquo;re all great in their own way. But after replaying this again (and again&amp;hellip;) I&amp;rsquo;ve made up my mind: it is the best Castlevania - period. It&amp;rsquo;s the second best Gameboy Advance title of all times according to IGN. Yes, I am insinuating it&amp;rsquo;s better than Symphony of the night. And yes, I know of the inverted castle&amp;rsquo;s greatness and the rip-off in Harmony of Dissonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Portrait of Ruin Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin-review/</guid>
      <description>Castlevania games tend to pop up each year on Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s Handheld platform. The last entries: Aria of Sorrow and Dawn of Sorrow, followed the story of Soma, who mysteriously inherited Dracula&amp;rsquo;s dark abilities. Forget about all that, and the soul harvesting system. Portrait of Ruin is the spiritual successor of Castlevania Bloodlines on the SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis. Jonathan Morris is the son of Bloodlines&amp;rsquo; whip-equipped hero. PoR takes place during or just after the second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handheld Castlevanias</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/handheld-castlevanias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/handheld-castlevanias/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Ruin is the second Nintendo DS Castlevania game. Maybe, if Komani thinks it&#39;ll be worthwile, a third one will follow, since there have been three Castlevania games released for the predecessor the Gameboy Advance. All excellent Handheld Metroidvania games, but which one excels at what? A short overview would be handy indeed. Well here you go! Gameboy Advance Castlevania: Harmony of Dissonance  Harmony of Dissonance was actually the second Castlevania game to be released on the GBA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>