<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefklaks Codex</title>
    <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefklaks Codex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jefklakscodex.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diablo III: Diablo for Kids</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/diablo-for-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/diablo-for-kids/</guid>
      <description>Ever wanted to play a real dungeon crawler but got held back by the possibility of a carpel tunnel syndrome? Did Diablo 2&amp;rsquo;s skill tree make you dizzy and the hard decisions on where to dump attribute points net you an increased blood pressure? No more, with Diablo III: Diablo for Kids! Cruising through the killing fields by the press of a single button. Forget health potions, character builds and scouring dungeons for loot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Circle of the Moon: a retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/circle-of-the-moon-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/circle-of-the-moon-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>As the hunt continues, from Aria of Sorrow to the beginning of Castlevania&amp;rsquo;s appearance on the GBA, Circle of the Moon, I have the uneasy feeling that my whip offers less solace in this scarier version of the castle. The encounter with an earth demon in the very first minutes acts as a warning for the rest of the game: be prepared to see YOU DIED a lot! Nathan Graves has to free his master from the clutches of - you guessed it - Dracula and partners, on the way avoiding the increasingly jealous Hugh Baldwin, the son of his master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Aria of Sorrow: a retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/aria-of-sorrow-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/aria-of-sorrow-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Calling Aria of Sorrow the best handheld Castlevania is quite a bold statement: they&amp;rsquo;re all great in their own way. But after replaying this again (and again&amp;hellip;) I&amp;rsquo;ve made up my mind: it is the best Castlevania - period. It&amp;rsquo;s the second best Gameboy Advance title of all times according to IGN. Yes, I am insinuating it&amp;rsquo;s better than Symphony of the night. And yes, I know of the inverted castle&amp;rsquo;s greatness and the rip-off in Harmony of Dissonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Switch&#39;-ing to the definitive nostalgic console</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/switching-to-the-definitive-nostalgic-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/switching-to-the-definitive-nostalgic-console/</guid>
      <description>The Nintendo Switch has been on active duty here for longer than I can remember myself playing on any of my previous home consoles. Of course the Wii had it&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Console service where Nintendo forced you to pay another 5 EUR for NES, 8 EUR for SNES and 10 EUR for N64 games that were carefully, week by week, re-released. It must have been the fourth time I&amp;rsquo;ve bought the Legend of Zelda: a Link to the Past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wario Land: a retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wario-land-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wario-land-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over 20 years since I last touched any of the Wario Land games. I vaguely remember them being one of the most exciting platformers I&amp;rsquo;ve ever played as a kid. However, thanks to my manic tidying itches, I sold most if not all Gameboy games I&amp;rsquo;ve ever owned. Thanks to a recent resurgence in retro game interest, I came across a Wario game for the Gameboy. The shopkeeper sold them all 4 and raised his brow when I wanted to pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BG2 Solo Blade: A Report</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-solo-blade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-solo-blade/</guid>
      <description>Report Content  Soloing - the Introduction The Blade Kit explained Used Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate II Setup Part 1: Irenicus&amp;rsquo; Dungeon Part 2: The Circus Tent &amp;amp; Slums Slaves Part 3: A Tanner &amp;amp; More Slaves Part 4: The Astral Prison Part 5: Daystar &amp;amp; Mae&amp;rsquo;Var Part 6: Some Beholders &amp;amp; a Lich Part 7: Druid Grove &amp;amp; Guarded Compound Part 8: Planar Sphere &amp;amp; Kangaxx! Part 9: The Shadow Temple</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BG2: Cleric/Ranger Guide</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-clericranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-clericranger/</guid>
      <description>Guide Content  Introduction to the cleric/ranger Basic progression guide Picking your equipment The cleric/ranger&amp;rsquo;s spell picks  
Introduction to the cleric/ranger Since little non-playable and joinable characters are as good in healing as Viconia is, you might end up creating your own cleric. Especially if you intend to play as a neutral or good party. Remember Viconia and Keldorn both at the same time in your party is asking for trouble: either one of the two will leave or they might even fight in later stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Mage Talk</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-magetalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-magetalk/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered whatever the heck those crazy Arcane spellcasters say every time they unleash one of their spells upon you? It&#39;s actually very simple and stands for the chosen spell&#39;s spell school (abjuration, evocation, ...). Male and female voices are of course different, and the pronunciations vary too sometimes (Vita Mortis [Carero]/[Calia]?). All formulaes are actually Latin, and Latin is often pronounced differently depending on the dialect. Here is a quick overview:  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizardry 8: Classes Guide</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wizardry8-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wizardry8-classes/</guid>
      <description>The Bishop Race Best Races:
 Fairy: best INT &amp;amp; SPE. Downside: low PIE and almost no weapons/armor usable. (go for sprite daggers if you want close-combat) Elf: good INT, PIE &amp;amp; DEX. Downside: less than fairies but you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use better armor &amp;amp; weapons (use staffs, maces &amp;amp; shield - you need AC - or throwing) Other good races: gnome, human. Mook for SEN + DEX.  Controlling attriubutes:  Intelligence (max ASAP for power cast &amp;amp; keep on pumping this power skill!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etrian Odyssey Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/etrian-odyssey-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/etrian-odyssey-review/</guid>
      <description>Old School dungeon crawlers. It has been a long time since we&amp;rsquo;ve seen these types of games properly released. Veteran Roleplaying players should remember Eye of the Beholder, the Bard&amp;rsquo;s Tale, Might &amp;amp; Magic, Wizardry and other series, released upon different non-console platforms: DOS, Commodore 64, Amiga, &amp;hellip; These games all used to have a few things in common, as explained in the Roleplaying Concepts article. The most intersting gameplay mechanic is without a doubt the &amp;ldquo;dungeon crawling&amp;rdquo; principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizardry 8: General Tips</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wizardry8-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/wizardry8-tips/</guid>
      <description>Legal notice: Most tips, tricks, howtos and guides are - not - originally created by me. They are scattered throughout the Internet, and this site contains a bunch of information found on other sites. Therefore, I am not responsible for any wrong information, or grammatical faults. If anybody notices his own text and would like to have it removed, please email me!
  A warm welcome to you, stranger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hype Train</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/the-hype-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/the-hype-train/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure most of you know the feeling. A new game has been recently announced, maybe with some additional gameplay footage or early concept art. You knew from that point on, the game had to be great, no mistake made. A couple of logical reasons could possibly be:
 The title is a sequel to your favourite game all time The title comes from a well known and loved development studio Both title and studio are completely new or unknown, but the genre is to your liking None of the above apply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum: Magick VS Tech</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-magick-vs-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-magick-vs-tech/</guid>
      <description>First things first: you are not reading this wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s magick and not magic. In the world of Arcanum, that is. There&amp;rsquo;s also no such thing as mana or spellbooks. Every single spell you learn comes trough {+SPs+) (Skill Points) which you&amp;rsquo;ll have to invest into several magickal realms. A little bit like Diablo 2, except the fact that once you&amp;rsquo;ve put 1 point into it, you can&amp;rsquo;t raise it further to increase the power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum: Party Seleciton</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-parties/</guid>
      <description>Party Numer ONE - November 2004
 Level - 25.
Laprovski - Male Dwarf - Raised by Monks
Skills - Technologist: firearms, gunsmithy, electricity &amp;amp; explosives
Stats - First PER Second INT Third DEX After a few tries, this dwarf managed to get himself to Tarant. There, the beautiful game acutally started with so many options - especially for technology! The dozens of shops give you plenty of possibilities and you&amp;rsquo;ll never run out of your own gadgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum: the Gunslinger</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-gunslinger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-gunslinger/</guid>
      <description>Overview
All right, you want yourself a cool character with even cooler guns. The problem is: technology is not that easy in Arcanum. Especially all the different schemes, guns, carrying the bullets, and so on. Would you like to make a backup plan, like throwing or a bow? Or would you just like to grab yourself an axe and whack the enemy when you run out of bullets? Or would you go running and rely on your followers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arcanum-review/</guid>
      <description>Hooray hooray for classic urgh-so-bad-graphics-but-so-good-gameplay RPG-games like this! Arcanum is without a doubt the best game Troika ever made, and that deserves something extra. Like a review and a nice collection of screenshots, or something similar. Enough introduction, grab a gun and shoot! Or pick a spell and cast, if you will.
What&amp;rsquo;s going on, George?
Finetuning has never been more fun
As some of you probably already know, this is a very strange game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arx Fatalis: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arxfatalis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/arxfatalis-review/</guid>
      <description>Not many first person action Roleplaying games are well known, except the Ultima Underground series and of course the Elder Scrolls games. FP RPGs date back from Wizardry, Eye of the Beholder and Might &amp;amp; Magic (see Roleplaying Concepts), but none of those games actually enable you to swing with a sword in a real time fashion. The Gothic games utilize the third person camera angle, so the only games which might get remotely close to being Arx Fatalis are Daggerfall/Morrowind and Ultima Underworld.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Party Guide</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-parties/</guid>
      <description>Party Number TWO - 06 Jan. 2006 (download link no longer available) Party Numer TWO - 06 Jan. 2006   Attitude: Xandarr, my main character. I decided to create a melee divine spellcaster, for the very first time, since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Arcane Magic way too much. I ended up with three members who are able to cast divinity spells, which is awesome. Xandarr is also the main melee mob killer, besides Keldorn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baldur&#39;s Gate 2: Spell Protection</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-spellprotection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-spellprotection/</guid>
      <description>Lots of misunderstanding exist for breaking through the spell protections of high level spell casting creatures. This guide is an almost exact copy of zvijers guide at the gone forgotten wars forum, also carried on by &amp;ldquo;The Hero&amp;rsquo;s Guide to a Successful adventure&amp;rdquo;. I found this to be very informative and vital for solo runs. The strategies explain mage protections in weimer&amp;rsquo;s Tactics modification.
All credits go to Xyx, Alson and Littiz for their Spell Reference Guide!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs Are Features</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bugs-are-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bugs-are-features/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting fairly tired of defending Arcanum on various cough, console lovers message boards and against friends. Everybody seems to prefer Oblivion-style Roleplaying gameplay mechanics. Fine by me, but don&amp;rsquo;t try to piss RPG Codex members and me off by complaining about the bug fest in Troika&amp;rsquo;s games. During my more than 5 playthroughs (admittedly never got to the finish, fooling around with different characters is even funnier), I never encountered a single &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lode Runner Returns Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/lode-runner-legend-returns-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/lode-runner-legend-returns-review/</guid>
      <description>Core mechanics A concept almost as old as Pong, the Godfather of nowadays gaming. You climb up and down little ladders, collecting various forms of loot. And guess what - you&amp;rsquo;re being chased by blood thirsty (well yeah, sort of) eurhm, red humanoid shaped things. On your way through each puzzle, there are multiple ways of dealing with them. From digging a hole and watching earth grow as fast as it can, squashing the enemy, to picking up little and very big bombs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riviera: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/riviera-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/riviera-review/</guid>
      <description>Riviera: the Promised Land is the Roleplaying debut game of the japanese developer Sting, released on the Gameboy Advance in 2005. Riviera actually tries to be two things at once: a classic japanese Roleplaying game on a Handheld system, and something more unique. What Riviera without a doubt manages to do is put down an excellent soundtrack. In fact, the inspiring tunes and tracks are of one of the highest quality music I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard on the GBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 2D Platforming</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/win-platforming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/win-platforming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Platform games, one of the most dominant game genres in gaming history. They spawned a whole lot of spin-off series (run-and-gun, platform puzzles, Apogee&amp;rsquo;s shareware system, Mario 64&amp;rsquo;s 3D platform debut). Platform gaming has been the dominant type on every gaming platform for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlevania Portrait of Ruin Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin-review/</guid>
      <description>Castlevania games tend to pop up each year on Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s Handheld platform. The last entries: Aria of Sorrow and Dawn of Sorrow, followed the story of Soma, who mysteriously inherited Dracula&amp;rsquo;s dark abilities. Forget about all that, and the soul harvesting system. Portrait of Ruin is the spiritual successor of Castlevania Bloodlines on the SEGA MegaDrive/Genesis. Jonathan Morris is the son of Bloodlines&amp;rsquo; whip-equipped hero. PoR takes place during or just after the second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handheld Castlevanias</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/handheld-castlevanias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/handheld-castlevanias/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Ruin is the second Nintendo DS Castlevania game. Maybe, if Komani thinks it&#39;ll be worthwile, a third one will follow, since there have been three Castlevania games released for the predecessor the Gameboy Advance. All excellent Handheld Metroidvania games, but which one excels at what? A short overview would be handy indeed. Well here you go! Gameboy Advance Castlevania: Harmony of Dissonance  Harmony of Dissonance was actually the second Castlevania game to be released on the GBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPG Concepts: Items</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-items/</guid>
      <description>Items present in the World Did you ever play an RPG, wondering why the world is so empty? Do you ever wonder, while entering a noble house without any real permission, why all closets are empty or not even openable? If you happen to like looting everybody&amp;rsquo;s treasure chests, bepare to be disappointed as some wealthy NPCs keep two single gold pieces in them. Wow! The RPG world &amp;ldquo;contents&amp;rdquo; should also reflect the current neighborhood you&amp;rsquo;re traveling in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPG Concepts: NPCS</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-npcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/rpg-concepts-npcs/</guid>
      <description>Watch the NPC Reaction video tests! &amp;gt;&amp;gt;
An NPC is basically a character not controlled by the player, who can be of great importance during the many main or side quests. NPCs vary in importance and placement: they can either be annoying and useless or interesting and useful. Many Role-playing games only give the most important NPCs something useful to say or do. Talking to other characters makes no sense since they only answer with one of the standard sentences: &amp;ldquo;oh, you&amp;rsquo;re the princess!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressive GBA RPGs</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gba-rpgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gba-rpgs/</guid>
      <description>Since the Nintendo DS has been released a couple of years ago, many game related websites predicted a quick and painful death for the Gameboy Advance. Thankfully, none of those predictions made it into reality since the GBA library is still steadily growing, although a whole lot slower than in 2002. Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s smart marketing ideas enabled the DS to play GBA cartridges which indirectly prolongs the overall GBA&amp;rsquo;s life. Therefore, a lot of potentially great games have been released but mainly ignored in favor of less entertaining DS games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon The Sorcerer 2 Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/simon-the-sorcerer-2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/simon-the-sorcerer-2-review/</guid>
      <description>Simon the Sorcerer II: &amp;ldquo;The Lion, the Wizard and the Wardrobe&amp;rdquo; is an adventure game from the British game company Adventure Soft who also produced the prequel, Simon the Sorcerer. The Simon adventure games are well known for their absurd and mostly weird British humor. If you do not like Blackadder and company, don&amp;rsquo;t bother installing this game. Simon 2 features many references and funny jabs to to popular literature, pop-culture, fantasy and other adventure-games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BG2/Infinity Engine Mods</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bg2-mods/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s modular Roleplaying game Neverwinter Nights 2 was released. NWN is well-known for its overwhelming amounth of fan-made modules and even whole Community Packs. This is the result of BioWare&amp;rsquo;s powerful Aurora Engine toolkit, which came packaged with the game. So actually it&amp;rsquo;s not that strange the game gets so much attention - take a look at UT2004&amp;rsquo;s numberous modifications or Total Conversions: with UnrealEd this is all possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Shooter Clones</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/early-shooter-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/early-shooter-clones/</guid>
      <description>People feeling nostalgic can play enhanced versions the games: For Quake, you&amp;rsquo;ll need:
 ezQuake Win32 Installer (Just install in a directory) Pak0.pak Quake Demo version (Or copy pak0 and pak1 from your original Qake) Create a new dir in the ezQuake install dir called &amp;ldquo;id1&amp;rdquo; and Unzip pak0.pak Play! (start with ezstart, press ESC in the console!)  For Duke3D, you&amp;rsquo;ll need:
 eDuke32 Win32 Installer (Just install in a directory) Duke3D Demo - only keep DUKE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback: Bullfrog</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bullfrog-flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/bullfrog-flashback/</guid>
      <description>The gaming development industry is a harsh world, especially since 2005. Publishers keep demanding more value for buck which often results into many game delay periods. Sometimes it may even end up real bad: the development studio will be forced to shut down due to lack of funds, popularity, hype, or other factors. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at one of the entrepreneurs of video gaming, Bullfrog Productions, and how exactly the company met the final end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Cooperative (PC) Gaming</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/cooperative-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/cooperative-arts/</guid>
      <description>What could possibly more fun than playing a PC game on your own? Why, cooperative gameplay mechanics of course! Every modern released game nowadays features at least one cooperative (co-op) game mode where you can play with your friends, mostly against the computer AI. Since this is part I, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Strategy games on the PC and its coopeartive capabilities. I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly imagine a strategy game without multiplayer options available, even games from 1998 came with some (limited) multiplayer modes, mostly using the IPX protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Killing a Lich</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/on-killing-a-lich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/on-killing-a-lich/</guid>
      <description>Both old school and modern roleplaying games feature many times at least one &amp;ldquo;Lich&amp;rdquo; entry. And the evil spellcasting undead creature will almost always kick your butt without proper protection. And why is it that so many big boss battles featuring some kind of super evil incarnation always have to transform into even worse enemies? Even Ganon tricked me in A link to The Past, although he is certainly not classified as Lich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apogee&#39;s Legacy</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/apogees-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/apogees-legacy/</guid>
      <description>Skip to the Videos part!
Only the new and young generation of gamers might not be familiar with Apogee Software - that is, until one has read the article. Apogee, the legacy of shareware PC games. I remember everything like it was yesterday! Impatiently receiving my first oversized floppy disk containing a demo version of Cosmo&amp;rsquo;s little adventures, racing through the first few levels of Duke Nukem, defeating way too much zombies in Monster Bash, capturing the first castle in Mystic Towers, &amp;hellip; The video game company literally created the shareware distribution model using various monthly subscribed magazines and one free floppy which was without a doubt numberous times passed on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jagged Alliance 2 Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/jagged-alliance-2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/jagged-alliance-2-review/</guid>
      <description>After the successful and beloved Jagged Alliance squad-based turn-based strategy game (a whole mouth full), Sir-Tech expanded the genre by adding the sequel, Jagged Alliance 2, which was published later in 1999. On a side note, it&amp;rsquo;s sad to see the JA series become more and more popular thanks to mass download methods like Steam, after the virtual death of the company itself. Well anyway, decide for yourself if the purchase (while you&amp;rsquo;re at it, nab the Gold version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Might and Magic VII: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/might-and-magic-vii-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/might-and-magic-vii-review/</guid>
      <description>In the year 1999 the then-existing company New World Computing released version seven of their honored Might &amp;amp; Magic series, subtitled &amp;ldquo;For Blood and Honor&amp;rdquo;. Most Might &amp;amp; Magic [-(MM)-] fans were quite happy since VII is by many people marked as (at least one of) the best in the series. Sadly, even New World Computing disappeared in 2003 and Ubisoft the gaint looking evil company bought all NWC rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeus Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/zeus-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/zeus-review/</guid>
      <description>Argh, my temple, all messed up! Poseidon likes to destroy all buildings I carefully planted down on the coast line because he&amp;rsquo;s cranky in the morning. Acually I did not do him a favour in the past few years and instead joined forces with one of the other major Greek Gods. What choice would you make? A couple of free superman-like heroes fighting side by side with your gaint army, or a couple of free boats to roam and rule the sea?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gobliins 2: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gobliins2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gobliins2-review/</guid>
      <description>Goblin Princes are Ugly Am I the only one wondering what the heck the lead artist ate the day he created Goblins? Uh oh, did I spell this wrong? Not really. In Gobliiins, the prequel, you can control three Goblin creatures, hence the three &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;-s. This game comes with two wacky dudes and the sequel with only one.
Every year an article pops up about Adventure games and the death of the genre and every year a fantastic game gets released to counter this myth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captain Claw Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/captian-claw-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/captian-claw-review/</guid>
      <description>Ah, 2D platformers. This genre disappeared after the DOS era on the PC. Also the consoles liked more the 3D platform games like hundreds of Mario 64 clones. There was almost never an attempt to revive the classic 2D side-scrolling action and add a few modern elements to it. Except for Monolith Productions of course! We know Monolith mostly from First Person games like the recent F.E.A.R. and of course the No One Lives Forever series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal Crossing: Wild World Adventure Blog</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/animalcrossing-wildworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/animalcrossing-wildworld/</guid>
      <description>The Cornimer is Here! [ Date: 09/10/2006 | top ]
Yes! The Acorn festival starts today! I managed to grab 15 acorns as quickly as I could, excited to see the legendary Cornimer pop up next to my Town Hall. He seems to like me so far, I received a Mush Chair and End Table in exchange for his acorns. Pfew, luckily I threw the rotten ones away. Oh yeah, and it&amp;rsquo;s Drift&amp;rsquo;s Birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jefklak&#39;s Codex: About</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About the Codex Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Jefklak/Wouter and you&amp;rsquo;re looking at &amp;ldquo;Jefklak&amp;rsquo;s Codex&amp;rdquo;, a dedicated and highly opinionated website1 about nostalgic games. The word nostalgic should be emphasized here. I grew up with a Gameboy between my hands and PC RPG games burnt into my retina. That healthy cocktail left a lasting impression - and netted me the Codex (and glasses).
The Codex has a long history, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt the need to proclaim my definitive game of each generation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>