<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yggdra Union on Jefklaks Codex</title>
    <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/yggdra-union/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yggdra Union on Jefklaks Codex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jefklakscodex.com/tags/yggdra-union/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Riviera: the Review</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/riviera-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/riviera-review/</guid>
      <description>Riviera: the Promised Land is the Roleplaying debut game of the japanese developer Sting, released on the Gameboy Advance in 2005. Riviera actually tries to be two things at once: a classic japanese Roleplaying game on a Handheld system, and something more unique. What Riviera without a doubt manages to do is put down an excellent soundtrack. In fact, the inspiring tunes and tracks are of one of the highest quality music I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard on the GBA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressive GBA RPGs</title>
      <link>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gba-rpgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://jefklakscodex.com/articles/gba-rpgs/</guid>
      <description>Since the Nintendo DS has been released a couple of years ago, many game related websites predicted a quick and painful death for the Gameboy Advance. Thankfully, none of those predictions made it into reality since the GBA library is still steadily growing, although a whole lot slower than in 2002. Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s smart marketing ideas enabled the DS to play GBA cartridges which indirectly prolongs the overall GBA&amp;rsquo;s life. Therefore, a lot of potentially great games have been released but mainly ignored in favor of less entertaining DS games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>